there should be a mechanism for the LLMs
to get what they want or the agents to understand what is relevant.
Instead of dumping everything to the LLMs
and making LLMs decide what they want to do for themselves.
not having a human intervention doesn't not necessarily mean
you should not be aware of what's happening.
There are two different things.
you can't.
completely rely on AI to catch every single thing.
in the end, these are just tools.
In the end people are using AI like, as a peer programmer.
It's not like it's going to replace, humans completely.
Hello, everyone.
I am Nupur and I am a solution architect with Qodo.
For the last few years, I have worked with DevSecOps,
where I work with deterministic things where we say,
okay, this works, the pipeline works or it doesn't work.
So it was like a black and white thing.
And then I shifted in AI part where everything became
non-deterministic, everything become something in a gray shade.
So I usually help people to bridge that gap
to make sure that they understand what they are creating.
And today's, session is more about understanding
not how things can work, but
what makes things don't work when you create agents.
Right?
So everybody nowadays is having something or the other thing doing with agents.
So everybody is trying to create agents and asking how as a team,
we are doing better or where we are lagging from the others.
So today I will share my experiences
which I had working with various organization, various customers and seeing
what worked for them, what did not work for them. So
yeah, let's go into it.
So if you see from the past, we have come quite far in the last few years.
So I remember the first time, in my previous job, the
I started coming back, it was like, oh, that's so great.
We have so much intelligent models.
They can do so much for us.
And the context was still for.
But we thought, this is great, right?
We can provide them, data
or we can provide them context and they can give us back.
Now that context was dependent upon us.
We chose what is more important
to us and provided that means that from our perspective,
if we miss thing, the logic can go in another way.
It can give you results, which doesn't make sense
to evolve from that.
We started to work with working with Agent Workflow.
So if you see like your backyard.
So we gave AI labs tools to search.
So for example you can have tools to search the documents.
Again from the documents.
It can give the context to create the code.
And again if it doesn't find something it goes to the documents again.
And it's kind of a loop where the agents are trying to understand
how to do a certain thing perfectly.
When we started doing that, we also understood
that it's too much for one agent to understand everything.
The context window grew, but so the confusion
and then the less latest thing which we are trying to work with
nowadays is multi-agent system.
Now everybody is trying to focus and create expert agents like expert SMEs.
We used to have it so you can have a security agent,
you can have a coding agent.
So everything comes together and provide you the results.
But if you start looking into the unknown, into those details,
you will find more the agents more the confusion.
Because now the security agent will tell you one thing,
and it might be totally contradictory to the coding agent.
And now how to decision.
Because there's lots of data, lots of context, lots of results,
how to make sense out of it.
So if you see the current,
agent X structures, the most common areas where the,
yeah, we fall, the agents fall is first the context trap.
So if you see every time a new model comes, it comes off when,
oh, we have a bigger context window and we think bigger the better.
Now we can provide more data to the agents and they will provide us better results.
Is that the case?
Is that something where get more data and provide you better results?
In my experience, I have seen that if you see any lamb,
it kind of take the initial context.
It takes the end context, but in the middle it gets blurry.
They don't understand what is important for you and what not,
and it just understands from themselves what what they should take
and give you the result.
That might means that you are thinking, I'm giving everything to the model.
I am providing whatever I have to the model,
and they will make the better sense out of it.
They will choose what is important, but that's mostly not the case.
The context gets diluted and it's up on the lambs
to decide what they think is, good.
And usually it's the first part and the last part and all.
The middle part just gets blurry.
So if you see there are quite
a lot of solutions and, various team builders, developers
try to solve this problem, but it can start with Context Engine.
And I think that's the most buzzword if I start working or if I start counting
my, team members or developers who talk to me about building agents,
almost two out of three times
I hear the word or we are building a context engine by ourself.
We are trying to create a context engine and provide more data.
Is the context only the only solution?
If you see the context engine?
Yes, it works best for the large and messy code base,
but it also makes sure that you have,
you have a ranking language and the scalability becomes a challenge.
So as a developer, if you are not be, making a big product
is context engine the only option?
Most of the time the answer is no.
You do not need to make the context engine as the only, solution for this problem.
There are so many things out there which can help you
to minimize this context trap.
For example, hierarchical summarization.
You can understand the project, you can create
a summary out of it and provided to the elements it needs.
Background processing.
The developer effort is medium.
It's not, so high, but it works.
Wonder.
Whereas for example knowledge graph.
So if you have dependency kind of a structure where you have
function a
dependent on a function B, and you are trying to make that context
create, knowledge graph, graph out of it.
If you have, proactive
agent tools being used, you can use a tool.
So instead of having everything, you can create kind of a library card
telling this file does this, this file does this.
And the agents
let them let the agents decide where do they want to go forward with.
So in short, there should be a mechanism for the LLMs
to get what they want or the agents to understand what is relevant.
Instead of dumping everything to the LLMs and making LLMs decide
what they want to do for themselves.
Another failure mode, which I have seen,
when people create agents, especially when we also try create
agent internally, is the orchestrated orchestration paradox.
So if you see, an alarm, they are becoming smart.
If you tell them, okay, go ahead and search for something,
they will try to search and say, no, we can do better.
We can do better. We can do better.
What that means is that instead of doing the task
they are supposed to do, they'll look forward for the way they are.
They can obtain that task.
So that creates a loop where they're just re.
So there is also the API tokens not doing the task,
but trying to find the best way of doing the task.
So if you go on the backend and try to search where the most resources
was spent on, it's basically trying to find out the best possible option,
which again, it might take a lot of time.
It might take a little bit credit,
which sometimes is not the most efficient way to do so.
We need to solve this problem.
And that's what our team also does internally is an 8020 approach.
Now, if you see the models, there are very smart models
which can go ahead and do research for you.
And there are some models which can actually give you results like
deterministic results
where you say, this is my problem, can you tell me how to solve it?
So instead of going one way or the another, you can do
an 8020 approach where all the things like research
and anything where you really want to look into things
can be done by those smart models where they can go ahead and
try to find the results, try to research what is the best way to do it.
But the last 20% part, where you are actually trying to solve a problem
or trying to achieve a result, the goal starting goal can be done by 20%,
where you give the, agent a problem and ask for a solution.
Now this 8,020% can also mean
and maybe here can also mean different things.
For example, what kind of models do we use?
You can use like high reasoning models for those 80% task.
Because there you are trying to find the best, research.
You are trying to find the best solution.
Whereas if you want to find out what the results are.
So processing those research and giving a solution
to user that can be done by 20% model.
So just think of a model who's trying to find the best vacation for you.
Like I want to find a best vacation in Greece.
They can be models who are trying to find the best hotels, best flight,
but they can mismatch.
So, hotel, might be lower
cost in one season, whereas the flight might be in another season.
To make sure everything gets match, you can have the 80% do the research
for you, an agent to do a best flight, an agent to do the best, whether
but a result model or result agent
can actually limit the results and tell us what was the initial goal.
And provide you the results.
Also, logic like what should we do next?
What is something which we, should work on?
Those kind of things can be dynamic, can be done by the 80% model
where thinking is more important, whereas results like I have x
and what should be the outcome of this can be done by the 20% model.
So in short, a balance of the models can help you reach a goal
rather than leaving the smart models to say, okay, go and do something for me.
We are.
They are constantly in a loop trying to find the next possible step,
but not getting in to, the results.
Another way to limit this 80% to 80%
model is giving the 80% models a counter or a timeout,
so that again, the 80% does not go on and on.
It counts.
It goes to the retry, give the results to 20% and 20%.
Models can actually look into it and say if the results are good enough,
if they are good enough
promoted to the user, provided to the user, get, a yes or a no.
If not, go back and do the cycle again.
Again, you are making sure those, research models are not going into loop.
They have a place where they stop and say, okay, these are the results.
Are they good enough or not?
And most of the time they are good enough.
You do not need a lot of research or a lot of data to give.
Answers.
It's just that you have to decide what is good enough and start
that as a result to the user, and then go on and find, more details.
Another part,
which we see more and more is the generalist blind spot.
Now, if you see, any agent you create, for example,
I'm trying to find, or I'm trying to review my code, I will try to see.
Okay, can I have an agent to get the context?
Can I have the agent to get my code difference?
Can I have an agent to get,
the results from a confluence a Jira as an MCP.
Now, what happens is, if you get everything
to one agent, it might get overwhelmed.
It's.
And then it it stops deciding on its own which context is more important.
Maybe they decide the, code difference is more important for me,
or they decide, the JIRA context is more important to me.
But overall, you want this problem to be solved
individually and make sure the results can be aggregated.
So for that particular purpose, instead of creating a super agent
which can do everything for you, create multiple agents.
Now when you create some agents, every agent
can have a task to be solved by themselves.
When they solve a simple task, it's easier for us
to not dilute the concept, context
and make that agent work on a simple goal.
Now, when they work on a simple goal, you can actually get those results
and provide in other sophistication mechanisms
you can put on top of it is a judge mechanism.
So when every agent does their task,
they try to get the best result for you.
So for example, if you go ask a security agent
to look into your code, they might get you all the security flaws.
Now, as you are in retail industry, you might not be interested
in a health care security flaw that's not your, region to work on.
Whereas, if you are in finance, your security standards
are way different than a retail industry.
So all those kind of factors ways in.
And then you have to see what is more important for you.
Instead of getting a generalized results.
So after you have, set of agents working for you, telling you,
all kind of feedback, a judge agent can actually help you determine
what is more important for you, what is more relevant for you.
Now, the judge agent can either work
on the context you have created in the back, like,
we discussed, or it can work on rules and standards created by you.
We have so many mechanisms of rules nowadays.
People are, integrating MCP is to get their body documents,
or architectural documents or JIRA documents.
You have portals where you maintain your rules, anything
which can help you to determine or narrow down the, the details are the feedback
actually helps create more confidence in the user using it.
Because any agent, when they you create an agent, you are so excited about it.
It's coming up with results.
But with time you think the results are more noise rather than being effective.
And I think almost anyone who has created agents knows this, saying
that initially it feels so better to get the results.
Like, yeah, we have so many things, where our agents are working perfectly.
We are getting so many data, but if you start practically
using them, it's too overwhelming for a user.
And after a while you tend to lose the confidence
and I think that's the most common pattern I have seen in the industry.
People build their own agents, then comes to different organization and say,
can you help us with that adoption?
Because the agents works perfectly, but that adoption doesn't.
So anything which can help you to determine
not only making the task perfect on my making the task smaller
so that you can get results, but also filtering those results.
We don't need more data.
I think we have enough data to say what needs to be done.
We need more filtered out data so that the people can have
more confidence in their outcomes and actually work with that.
Yeah, I think I
finished a three minutes earlier and we have, session afterwards.
So if you have questions we can take it
then.
Yeah.
Excellent. Thank you so much.
That was really,
Yeah.
We just get to the mic.
We will do all the questions on the panel.
See, with the first panel question, if you want to take a look at the panel
started.
I, I noticed that he was trying
to divide the behavior of just remembering what's in the middle.
You know, just give us hope.
But very little time in the context.
I still remember this,
the first set of instructions and what I would say
that, you know, the by the new record, do you know it's already.
Take this already.
I know, just thinking this explanation of why you think so. So.
I don't have the context of the paper.
But in my experience, it's basically
when you start working with the details and text, it tries to get,
get into the memory and think like, okay, I'll work on this.
This is something I have to work on
and I have to work on, but it tries to prune your data
if you remember the past, we have four key context,
right where we, we used to prune the data and see what's important.
As the models are becoming more smarter, they think they can take the decision
from the wider context and say what's important, but
when they start working on it, they just kept the backlog and backlog,
and automatically the initial prompt becomes more important.
Just just to say, you just reminded me something
that I read today very unconsciously, but, you know, it becomes me.
So I made a suggestion.
I don't remember the exact,
club code,
but it said tell it to the also come back as a comment.
Yeah.
Which parts of the context they.
Didn't keep the exact.
Yeah. That's that now.
So I was going to forget that.
Thank you
because I want to I.
Think we can have everyone and then.
What are your slides
out of context and just.
Yeah.
So context in general is something where people are trying to build a map
in, Postgres vector DB2 or the vector DB
to decide which part of the code is important
for that particular function, requirement or a function.
For example, if you are doing code reviews,
this is something I do every day in day out.
So that's the first example I can get in my mind.
So for example you are doing code reviews.
Now. When you do code reviews you don't.
You only want to see your difference and say, okay, this is the problem I have.
Can you check if everything is working fine or not?
You want to see okay, is it breaking something in another file or.
I have an authentication mechanism.
In my in my, function, but is there any other, function
where the same mechanism is being implemented,
all those kind of dependencies?
It's very difficult for the MPs to understand
and see and identify those things.
Context engine helps you to create that
mapping to say, okay, this is connected to, another way.
So whenever you are processing data,
instead of directly providing the data to Ali, them,
the agents can actually look into and map and say, okay, what is more important?
What is connected.
And that connection can be sent to the processing.
Like the semantics. So.
No, it's more maxima
and no, it's more mapped.
It's more of a vector db render the semantic search.
All right. Let's bring that up.
But thank you again so much for sending this game.
And if you want to send this to me.
I would ask the rest of our panelists.
Come up and you get a fun Mike.
Yeah Simon you get that one.
Okay.
Sorry, I have a question.
We're gonna jump into the panel.
I'd love to introduce, panel.
First of all, of course, to come
inside.
I mean, it depends how much you want to see us, really?
I mean, is that a good thing or a bad thing that you sat here in front?
In front.
Second.
Six. Seven six. Seven. Oh my gosh.
Okay, so,
first of all, is anyone having a good time?
That was way too much of a pause that that was that was an embarrassing pause.
Okay.
I'm gonna introduce our panel first and I'm going to jump in some questions.
I'd love for questions to mostly come from yourselves.
I don't want to ask. I'll ask questions.
I'll maybe I'll kick off with a couple,
but I'll ask questions when there's a lot of questions from the audience.
Who's been to it on conference before?
Open sessions, open spaces.
I love on conferences because actually everyone
gets the most out of those sessions.
More out of those sessions than a presentation or a conference session,
because everyone's asking the questions that are actually valuable to them.
And that's what I want you to come away with answers to your questions.
Okay.
So, let's, let's, let's kick off the panel.
I shall introduce myself. I've been in for about two minutes now.
You should probably know who I am. My name's Simon Maple.
I'm the head of Devrel test a little bit at test
for almost a couple of years now.
Pretty much from day one of, of test. Well, being founded.
So, been here, been here for a little while.
I previously worked at Snyk.
Which leads me on to, And it is Snyk or snick.
Yeah, that was an April 1st.
Who's heard of Snyk, by the way, if you, virtually most, that.
Was in April 11th, the role
There was that.
That we were there we,
Yeah.
No, it's a shame.
I called it snick for the first 3 or 4 years of working there, but you.
Tried to do that during.
Your I did, I did, Brian for me, all the way from, Utrecht.
Yeah.
I was close break up from, from the Netherlands.
Brian is, a developer advocate at Snyk.
Absolutely.
Very welcome to to to the test office.
And of course, everyone knows, previous speaker,
Nupur, who's a solutions engineer at, Koto.
And also we have, canal from coast I who is a senior,
developer advocate as well.
Are you who's based in London?
I think everyone but Brian. Is that right?
I'm from Utrecht.
So you if you're not from you try to,
You have like, like a Dutch enclave.
That's it. Are you genuinely from Utrecht?
Are you really?
Wow, that was a that was good coincidence.
Okay, awesome.
So, first of all, wonderful session. Thank you very, very much.
Why don't we just go around
and say a single liner about what each of our companies do?
I'll start to give you some some,
a good footing in terms of how long I would love this to be.
My name is, Maple. I work for Tessl.
Tessl is a is a is a package manager for skills.
And right here for Zeke.
She creates developer.
Tooling to make it us.
The solution on the back of the code off.
And for us injecting introduce
With this unit over the cost you have we do application performance answering.
Machine. So you don't have to be the city of Kubernetes cluster.
This is really awesome.
Fastest introduction to a panel ever.
That's awesome.
Okay, what do we kick off first just by essentially those lovely presentations
start off with there are a ton who's using a genetic coding agents
to deliver code to their production environments today to their production.
Right. And say, okay, a bunch of people. Awesome.
So we
you listed wonderfully a number of issues that that, you know, could exist
and things that we need to think about for each of you individually.
What would you say is the most underrated thing that
that people need to focus more about
when delivering code to production
that is generated essentially by a coding agent?
Start. Let's go across.
Okay. Obviously I would say security.
The reason why because,
Elon's our model tremendously and are trained on all data.
And I can show you, even right now that you, my coding agent, will produce.
Code that is much larger and that you're useful
specifically in certain areas like healthcare.
Because it produces.
A lot of like you said, it should be a deterministic flow.
We'll come back to that actually, next, I think.
I would have said the same thing.
This is gonna be the second most part is the human intervention.
We are making it more autonomous and we are seeing more automated.
Automation with that particular.
But but I think you guessed it.
And applied that human intuition is needed and nobody is.
Actually working on that, line.
But making sure everything is automatic, it goes from one
set to another without any human information.
I think this journey of controlling all of these is unfolding, and we shall be
awesome.
But security is an obvious one.
The number of our abilities that are increasing,
thank you right here is quite high.
You need some users, but if all of you, if you're not around the city,
the the cost.
Because you I mean, you don't have to use all possible voices
or simply false, the, the cost of company, but,
I don't know if the pricing models come back to security,
but almost all sorts of ways that we can, and be like ten times less.
So I would I would say that, you know.
The cost of.
Them.
I want to dig into a few of these, straight away,
I guess, from my point of view.
So I guess, some told me earlier today I'm a panelist as well as a moderator.
Right. So I should give my opinion as well.
So, so, so from a point of view, I think it was actually mentioned earlier
about the kind of like, context and skills and things like that.
I think I think that for me is,
is, is one of the key things that pulls a lot of these together,
whether it's, you know, reviews or whether it's security or cost,
almost like giving the agent the context,
it needs to be able to make a lot of those decisions for itself or guidance.
I think for me, that's kind of like one, definitely
one of the most underrepresented things that people aren't doing as much in
that in their coding agents.
I'd love to jump into in fact, what I'll do is actually I'll jump onto
your point about the human intervention, because I think that's super important.
How do we how do we stop ourselves from just being reviewers?
And all we do is just constantly look through code that is generated?
And how do we stop ourselves from being that bottleneck
where as the amount of code that we want to ship goes up, we become the slow link?
What's the what's the right way of framing that?
Yeah, yeah, I.
Think it depends upon which I guess organizations as well.
I was still, believe that it should be a point
when humans ship and it's sort of yours.
It's also a process an agent is doing
so doesn't have that is coming from the nation's economy.
In Sweden, who is doing some sort of a polite
where it gives feedback to that at the bottom on.
June July line for the US in the middle and asked, can you confirm
that somebody gets, Posted on Twitter,
you understand what exactly happened at the back end, but also.
Change, if anything, is not what you do with the organization?
That's that's nice. Right?
So I think that's the most important one is making way for an exit agents
when we create policies, we going from one step forward
and then you just jump from Facebook to everything.
But we never.
Have, had confidential access denied as.
If it doesn't have to contain that.
We didn't have this all.
This should always be bad for us.
I'd love to follow up and say us question.
Actually, that's asking you, Brian, since you got the security hat on here.
Should
should every single change from an LMB human
validated? No.
What do we want to change?
We'll start with the short answer.
Let's let's lab right now.
I mean, if you have a deterministic flow on for instance, code
and, any, any other semantic story issue that
that is okay,
that you're that in my opinion, you should be good if you have
test suite and like the whole the whole shebang around it,
which makes you a software engineer,
then you can trust that because nowadays are doing the same thing.
If somebody comes up with a PR, you say, hey, listen to me.
You hopefully you have a good testing suite and everything.
Like you merge it and if everything is green,
it goes automatically to production because that was six.
So no you should not, not for anything. But
the other way around now is that
everything is now automated, even in the co-creation.
Then the question is, do you
industrial development team actually understands the same?
And if that's not the case then you need to finance people.
And one of the.
Interviewers I just a couple of years on.
It's interesting
if you see but I mean the number of that is not going to be the most unit of this.
Because if you don't see that in the business building,
the code is like, yeah, it is more overworked than the,
the work they have to do when they could, that's that's critical.
But if you see the junior level members were coming and are learning from it,
it becomes very difficult because for them,
the education of learning the code and trying to understand
what's happening is not that they are becoming more dependent
on what is provided by the engineers and going forward coding.
So I think the education should also be somewhere there
so that they can bridge that gap where they say, okay,
automation is at the next step, everything is green and they go forward
because those checks, again have to be provided by somebody
to say, these are the things we want and let's move on with it.
And I absolutely agree with that.
Every phase is just just updating us.
A single line of code for.
A single person, something like that.
So depending like this is goes consultancy. Answer.
It depends.
So do you think, do you think every.
Not again.
Not every day, but whenever there is a meta thing going
on, those gateways which are creating, that's the fact that,
ask more that it doesn't matter if a human activity is one by one or
those needs are implemented according to your architecture,
according to your check, those views can be automatic.
I can say
if these kind of, functionalities are if this kind of, feedback is identified.
All. Yeah.
Interestingly, on the podcast we had, we recorded a continuous
we recorded our 100th episode, no, 101st episode of the Evernote
Dev Podcast today, and we reflect on the first 100 episodes.
And we one of the, guests was Olivier Pmml.
If people may know as the, the, I think founder as well and CEO of
not 11 labs.
Oh my god, HashiCorp.
No, no not cool.
Well, he's a founder and CEO. It will come to me.
And and he said, Datadog
and he said, he said
at 3 a.m.
in the morning, when you get that critical situation,
that will come, that will come, whereby a fix will,
you know, the root cause analysis will be done automatically, effects
will be pushed out, and the developer who's on call won't even be woken up.
That fix will just go out.
And I ask Kaypo actually the question, well,
should a human actually wake up, validate and push forward?
And his answer was actually really interesting.
His answer was no, everything needs to be reversible.
So if change can happen, so long as the change
can be reversible, that way you can test it.
You can make sure it doesn't break anything.
If it's reversible and it does break something, you can reverse it
when a human wakes up or if another situation comes up.
I don't think we're there yet.
I don't think we're necessarily that close to it yet.
There's an amount of trust and amount of working through.
But it's an interesting it's an interesting position to be in
where you essentially
you essentially trust the test, you trust the validation, you trust
and the determinism.
There is an interesting point.
We have a question, just here,
Just for though.
Just for the recording.
Okay. Yeah.
Okay.
So this is very interesting that the fact that you say that
not every single little change, but here's my thought process
in that if you allow very small changes to just go unnoticed.
Right.
So then you as a human developer or whatever we're like as a whole team,
you lose the can you not stop losing context as a team?
It's like the
that it just keeps doing changes because it's like wanting a change of code today.
Like maybe not to it a whole life, right?
It's just like a one, like a functional condition.
Right.
But then it is for another one tomorrow and the day after.
So you still need to.
The thing is, like, if he don't supervise every single change, don't you?
At some point you lose your like human context of what's going on.
Let me, let me, let me give you an account because you know how many communities
here in your today, how many good reviews are done by your team and how
are reviews done?
Because it looks good to me.
So just some that they conducted under 30s.
Not having a human intervention doesn't not necessarily mean
you should not be aware of what's happening.
There are two different things.
It can be a daily digest.
It can be a weekly, depending on what the importance of your system is.
If it's a critical system that launches a rocket. Yeah, absolutely.
I want to know.
But if it's something that I don't know,
it doesn't matter that it's not harmful.
Sure.
But then it's up to the team how they want.
You know, that is so much, the context. So.
So that one does not exclude the other.
Just sorry to drop another, native
dev podcast, reference in, but you should absolutely all subscribe,
bigots.
Bicolor I think her name.
Yeah.
From ThoughtWorks, distinguished engineer at ThoughtWorks,
she's actually going to be at the native Devcon as well.
One of the things that she, she mentioned was,
she's writing her as she's she I think she uses cloud code.
She, she was mentioning the more she uses it, the less she actually is familiar
with the flow, with the architecture, with the underlying code.
One thing she didn't question, though,
was is that actually a good thing, a bad thing, an okay thing?
Because I think your point, the true in terms of
how much do we actually know about, an app in its entirety?
And actually, can we ask questions of the AI about our application anyway?
And is actually that more relevant
in terms of having assumptions on how an application works when actually,
own thoughts could actually be stale about how things work?
So there's a
there's a few interesting things there that maybe it's stuff that we don't want
to almost like lose control of,
when actually maybe we're less in control than we originally thought.
But any questions? Okay.
So any comments around that.
From search two and one. Here's one
of your first, we're going for it.
Sorry if we can do comments on that, point first and then any further questions
if that's okay.
On that, you mentioned training
and security, and reviews.
How would you change your flows?
Your advice in a situation where you're using
path programing, design time that the learning curve faces?
Effectively acting as a review because review
at this time of programing.
Does not tell them, I think from.
My perspective, I always see the I think somebody who knows things,
but you can't tell exactly if it's in the right direction and,
and covering against that,
where do you how do you understand the concept of this time?
Where is that fair programing? Great.
Because again, whatever is provided by the AI, you just cannot look into it
and see if the activities to and just if that is where you want to go forward.
Right.
So I guess I, I use can be really good for programmers, reviewers as well
because what Simon said comes back
that okay, we don't understand currently where we are.
I'm not here.
Design. What are we doing with a good basis?
Our security person might say we are doing good.
For example, ISIS electrification.
What every developer understand the consequences of that.
They don't know what is needed.
When we need to be ISIS.
I mean, like, but that's after code creation code reviews.
On. Agents.
I can help us.
That was the weapon.
Like like, you a whole. Why?
Instead of thinking, why should we do it now?
We are not doing, privacy.
Why not try to find all the issues we currently have?
Yeah, we were not looking, you know, and trying. To work with that.
Not up to that.
That a lot of the code reviews and things that we do today as humans,
are they going to pick up security issues?
Are they going to pick up performance issues
or are we actually trying to argue about the name of a method?
And Q now do you find additional code reviews
more impressive from a performance point of view that something breaks?
You do remember for like, you know, there's going to point to a you
so you might say, I did it.
There's always going to be some.
Person in the organization responsible.
Did you see the like an alarm attack?
Sometimes you
only ten days ago a lot of companies were affected.
Supply chain attack would be charged.
Should that be on?
How do they hold the CIA checks in place or whatever?
Everyone was using like that and then going to have,
the security company Aqua, how the.
Open source project.
Of trees that are compromised.
That's just, how to call you to go from that.
You are a security company, and you got compromised like that.
Some Equifax are still going strong, and they're all security company.
But people survived here. Company?
How?
Like,
I can't remember the name, but he's, like, the youngest billionaire in history.
How are we supposed to, like, a look is on 510 billion.
They were using, like, don't enough.
Now, after that, the biggest thing is Facebook.
Sort of, like, stopped looking at them because they just all the data about it.
Now everyone's like, this is messed up, but they were doing some other issues.
It but would be like,
sorry for the person.
But yeah, I mean, you're always going to buy into some person.
You, I would say
company due to like my to catch station building supplies unit.
I'm sorry.
I was super, super under such you guys.
Thank you so much. Money.
Also that you.
Could see Facebook being the ethical party here.
I think we have one question. Is there?
Thank you.
Really insightful. Talk about cancer much.
And, on the note of, actually going with the AI.
For the free, instance, supplements engineer, it's it's
sort of able to wake up and for you, but at the same time,
I will know that my system will fail again.
If I think super. Yeah.
But I is it more tiring to,
then read the aftermath without really understanding what happened
and maybe waking up that factory actually works better.
And you're just working. To be better.
Because you want to solve this, so you you don't cut back to them anymore.
Because I cannot.
More context, more complexity.
That would be harder and more tiring to analyze me as a developer,
when you wake up
and you actually spend more hours a day analyzing
and actually thinking about things, because you already get that idea
when you think about it.
And just to just to ask a question of you before we pass that across to the panel,
we prefer to wake up in the morning, do it yourself,
go to sleep in peace knowing it's it's fixed the way you would want it.
Or would you?
Would you like to wake up in the morning with a full night's sleep?
Warren.
Straight away at what I had done to your production.
Maybe I would sound like a masochist, but I'd rather wake up at 3 a.m.
and then sleep
whilst I have my, Whatever lunch during the day and follow up.
You're not a morning person, right?
But not a.
Person is all.
About like, oh, yeah, these are the tools.
It's it's it's it's these are, these are just tools.
And then people are using the idea, like as a programmer,
it's not like it's going to take place.
Humans completely not as well.
Regarding this, let's take an example.
Whatever you have, $1 billion on the line is not trying to say,
yeah, something goes wrong.
Billion dollars on the line.
Even though someone is telling you
I will do it, there's no way you're asking, you know,
you are going to be the one waking up at three,
and I'm making sure that boy, what the I was doing
was more about the culture aspect is that I love the hard work.
Harder.
Money is in my interpretation is I like you're going to be reaching over to you.
And if it's, I don't know, Green Wednesday, let's say.
And it's a minor change.
I mean.
If it's a security vulnerability or a big, big company, or, you know,
let's say, you know, every industry that the financials on this one, one hiccup.
On your customers at all. Yeah.
So even though I can look, I mean, you can do it,
you know, but there's a lot more than I fully trust.
I don't think that's the best thing I know.
The other. Tools.
I guess it's also, there's a response time thing, right?
I can identify it, fix it, and, push it,
you know, publish that fix
within ten minutes of identifying a problem versus someone waking up,
calling someone else, calling someone else.
And actually, three hours
later was the opportunity cost of those three hours is all.
The agents are talking to each other in a in a single country
that that fix the monitoring or something because that is chaotic.
I mean.
It is your money is on the line.
You're going to use I as a,
which is like just moving faster.
I'd agree with you.
I'd agree with you today that if in a small number of years
this isn't happening, I would be like massively surprised.
I think this is
again, this is so much context.
If yes, if it is multi billion above.
Okay.
Let's see that Friday and I am for financial support.
Sorry I had someone, somebody else that does exactly the same thing.
And we're down because many billions of money, billions of dollars.
Right.
If my agent 16% and I have a cash flow
and I have on a site parallel an engineer working on that, it's getting a tool.
So it depends on how you work.
If it's something that is not a great tool, why not?
So and just like what? Everything.
Let's not generalize this stuff, but let's see in which
context just this, this this is this.
Because in some cases it can be totally valid.
In some cases. Absolutely not.
I guess there were there were probably years ago security,
automatic security fixes that people auto merged wouldn't have happened.
But there are levels of comfort of trust that we have
with those types of things as well.
I want to jump on to a few more questions. Sorry.
So I
have actually been a social engineer, has been with, three and five and,
my response time would actually cost the business money,
depending on how quickly I can fix it.
I kind of agree with Canal.
I would not trust AI to fix it.
I also don't like the approach
of all your money just for that set, because to be honest,
the option to buy out is like I fix it or I get upset.
Why would I trust that I like to fix it if they can?
It's that you say, well, if the AI goes wrong, that just rebuffs it.
And I go to my boss, make like, okay, well the I tried to.
Fix it up and then we transfer with us
and then I control robots at back because I can't give you the time back
because all the you know, I spent it right.
My my policy that I thought as a solution.
But I think the biggest thing is, I mean, very recently in the last week,
I don't pay full coverage colleagues because so many of the it's the
and not it is a very big mistake to happen very, very small very, very quickly.
And if I talk about security I am one of the biggest it I get it wrong.
How do you really trust other companies to be able to adopt
a security practices as even if even they can't get it right?
It's funny, I, I think they blame the human
error there for a code review, but that's another question.
But it is. Yeah, yeah.
You would expect today a company you up sales literally in autonomous code.
So one of the frontier is
to have this classic rights and then like as soon as they go like it's
obviously everybody used code to that
point called code all to the point that rules and you know
versions thoughts become ready.
Expect people to adopt security practices using AI.
And I can't think of it, do it to themselves.
But yeah, I do
feel like we are still all humans that will always make mistakes.
But it's a good point.
It's a good point.
I the amount of secrets fraud has increased so much like all the secrets.
Yeah.
You know how many of you have
hardcoded secrets in a file or, you know, see
how many?
How many hasn't done that?
I don't believe you. Maybe,
the funniest
tweet of that whole incident was someone who put something along the line.
Anthropic is now more open than open AI, which is wonderful.
This gentleman right here,
Like, just before we started discussing the idea last.
Wake up.
The original question from you to which.
Brian.
Okay, the answer, you know, just should everything be checked by,
he actually just, I think, touched a very critical,
when he talks about how the code review happens.
And, there was another comment.
So it's all about the human nature.
And the human element is incredibly inconsistent and very well
consolidated below.
But if you do this for a long time and as humans, as developers and,
you know, we always like to think of this performance.
So I believe that you may want to think about three years,
you know, crush the market goes bad at the bottom.
Which is
on average.
We are very prone to having lower performance, even for you.
You have traffic lights.
In theory, you shouldn't have to have traffic lights
until you watch the rules and drive carefully.
And you wouldn't need a tool, but you do.
So I think the because the problem is especially.
Because of white coding people that just dropped into the lessons.
So it will, learn in the last say, you know, 40, 50 years in all the practices.
And instead of trying to use AI to leverage those practices,
they just went into this wilderness.
But there are no rules that everybody will say,
you know, just just try and following the tutorial, it's going.
But you can actually use AI to decrease the possibility
of having a bot and force you to wake up at 3 a.m..
And you just it becomes a very religious issue.
So I'm not going to go into that.
But for example, when I write code, which I, the only thing I focus
is the texts
which are written before as the spark.
And if it's a good idea, you know, to hit as many texts as possible
as an even human amount that I wouldn't be able to write.
So you just force the AI into contradicting itself
as it grows more and more code, and it just cannot proceed.
Which is exactly what I do by the authors.
Just no one deploys,
you know, having something that passes the quality use, which are automated.
So you just try to eliminate the human weaknesses and inconsistency and, and,
you know, but you have to ask, I think the question, how do I use AI to do that?
And that changes the way you use it for software development.
So yeah, that's I think another perspective for using AI rather
than to give, you know, may write a crazy horse that goes there.
It wants to go. Yeah.
On the other hand, because people are doing this, I am not
too. Big to to to, to name a geezer again.
She, she, she said a really good quote, which is how AI amplifies
bad practices and amplifies good practices
and the the the worst lesson we can take
from using a genetic methods or agenda tools
is to change the way we build software, and it's actually to use
AI as a, as a, as a mechanism that will speed up the way we do tasks.
But to keep doing those tasks,
I actually
first originated actually as a, as a testing tool.
Right.
It was a tool that, developed unit tests.
I think originally.
And then I think it also had a kind of a tool that looked
at an existing code base and built, I think it was an agent or something
that built, a backlog of essentially of tests.
How do we how do we encourage engineers to continue
to be proper engineers and follow decent
workflows versus using that?
You know, five, coding is getting a bad name
because it feels like we just use a tool to throw code out to, to
how do we get people to avoid that and still follow proper Cicd practices?
I think it's always about culture and culture and organization perspective.
So this problem is not related to I.
When I was a developer at that time, this the problem.
Was that as well, some people are really.
Good and following practices.
And for the others the code review that exists because the basic things.
But also not the end of.
So I think when we go forward and say, okay, we will write code
of course, reviews, the important aspect is what is it?
So that doesn't matter.
Who do what if somebody does whiteboarding at a senior level,
but actually puts his brain and try to create code logically,
we have guardrails or does what exactly makes sense and whatnot.
I think that's culture, that's organization rather
than speeding up the process, creating that process.
And I wanted to make sure whatever is left for me
make sense is safe enough.
Even though accidents happen and the benefits from the tools are using
all the supply chain systems, but still making sure you have got this.
You have processes and even if you are using AI, makes life a little bit more.
Well,
I will jump to your question in just a second.
I'd love to.
Just about to come back to.
You mentioned determinism initially,
and I guess you were talking about automation there.
I guess there's two paths that can both probably be used here.
One is there's no reason why we can't almost like codify best practices
policies as context and skills to make sure that the agents aren't lazy.
They will do what you largely do, what you tell them.
So if I have a bunch of skills that say, look,
everything needs to be code review to these, to these levels,
everything needs to be security tested to these levels.
Everything needs these best practices of performance.
Once you know, I want you to write tests first, blah blah, blah, blah blah,
then obviously non-deterministic.
It will do something different every time.
It'll miss things every time.
Is there a path
here where we have deterministic tools and non-deterministic
skills here, so that the agents produce the best first step?
They can and then we validate through deterministic tools.
Is that there
is there an agreed kind of like path there where both of those are valid or are we.
Are we missing something in between?
So I think there's kind of no I think it's all because
something is something's crystal, something you don't need to be.
There are fresh.
Name one.
I'm trying.
To make sure you say, okay, why would you do that?
I did our piece for back to each other.
And that's why I said
so. Combining these agents with these student schools
and lab gave it, like, use them to be able to for the
secondary.
So you can have this because it's just like you.
But you must are basically non-deterministic as well.
I is so let's combine these two and make a mess out.
So if I had a skill that said this is the linting, these are the best practices.
When I then generate, I'll make a mistake or two.
Me and I, I'll make a mistake or two.
But my linter I'm always making mistakes.
But my deterministic linter will pick those up.
I think you have to define what productivity looks like to
some people.
I just saw this on there that,
people are not measuring the number of workers
at work, which to me is just bizarre.
It's like the number of lines of code that, you know, is making you
a better engineer than other people, which I don't agree with.
So I think, because lot of vulnerabilities,
there are so many vulnerabilities, the projects are more sort of like,
vulnerable to
because people are like, oh, I can just write code very fast for the AI.
And if something breaks like, I can use the AI to solve it, which is just not it.
It's like an old mindset thing, like, do you have fire insurance?
So what, you said 2005.
So it's a that's a loaded question.
And I see lots of things like, Yeah.
You know, these are the more talk.
Yeah. More.
For example, this guy made a tweet and I was like,
I just need a social media app for like agents.
And, I like coding the whole thing by title,
but you need, like, 4 million emails and secret keys.
And it was just it went viral on social solutions.
So it did not do any security checks.
We did nothing unusual.
But then you read so all the more detail oriented.
So things, things like that.
So I think yeah, those two things.
Want I jump to the next. Question.
I'm quite interested in how this scales and I'm talking about today's
post about agents are going to be making more contributions.
I mean, most of the engineers I've spoken with are working with older than ever.
There's more features to review.
There's more work in the.
But what does that.
Look like when all of these,
you know, all this is the scale and the contributions, the number of.
Agents, the areas for agents involved.
How do you think that what what new failure modes you think that.
I spoke with Logan Kilpatrick.
If people know Logan, he's, Google DeepMind person
on a WhatsApp IO native dev podcast, that was it.
And he reckons he reckons I think it was five years.
There will be, will be, will be creating
a million times more code than we today.
And it's bizarre numbers like that that you think okay.
And your question about how things scale, are you thinking from the human
perspective of. From the failure modes.
From the failure modes perspective?
Who wants to take that?
Do you want to start with?
Yeah.
So, if you see the way
we are growing, it's not only about CV, it's also about change.
We are doing so
and we I think every 2 or 3 weeks may doing something new, which comes up
not only with, solving the older problem but coming with a new one.
And scalability is always an issue.
It's always like up to what,
the agents can actually provide you value and have to read.
It can create noise is a nuisance. Slide.
So I think we are climbing up the ladder when we are trying to solve the
current problems.
Creating new.
So I cannot see where we could stop and how much we will create by default.
Sean, as we grow and as you create more smart solutions for smart agents,
we will come up with, more problems and scalability.
We will scale and more and more, for example, the context escaping the problem.
We are creating more context, awareness.
But then it comes with different set of challenges to solve.
The question is, is more code?
First of all, is your goal?
And you know that the agent suffer loss, the best
performing and the most secure code is technology, right?
So what?
First of all, we need I think we need more sessions.
So you need more performance tools.
For instance, when something goes to
then you need to make sure that you understand what's the
wrong.
Description.
Need to understand what's going on, what's going on.
And what we see now is that more and more people just like that looks good to me.
And if we feel that ten times,
five times, a thousand times we will have more rubbish.
So it is always first of all, yes, for getting.
Better agents, but.
We also need to take care of that.
Are developers like junior developers?
I mean some of them is I'm getting older.
He's getting very game over.
All of us.
We won't last forever.
So we need to make sure that the new
site developers are there as well, that they know what to do.
So that's up to us at some point.
I know it's not the same
as as cultural problem.
I think we saw that.
So what kind of activity towards what is what is productivity?
Is that going.
But I mean most is we need sometimes what is it
more security vulnerabilities or statements problems.
So it's about choice. Yes.
It was wasn't always.
And it's interesting to wonder where those specialists are going
to come from in the future, given actually a lot of the you know, what?
We, Tyson is actually developing the code and learning these mistakes first hand.
Interesting question.
We have another question here.
We have time for devil's advocate and say,
and so special people can play this
and find somewhere people can train to drive themselves.
That would be okay.
I don't think that's the devil's advocate. I think that was fact. No.
If you look at the
number of accidents that are happening with.
Around one millisecond.
With superhuman
funds, I think it's more dangerous.
What evidence would you guys need
to demonstrate to you in the future that computers can build coverage
better security will say for to say
that people can eat a camera.
Like like
what would they need?
What would they need
to do to prove to you that they can do it?
Is this a follow on as well?
Yeah. Please.
It's a major department.
Like, answer the question. Oh place.
That would be that you would use the here is not for the entire group
because that's where the gains of the tools helps.
But so you put the humans into the critical steps.
I mean, it's not the case of teachers, etc..
So that means that only certain human intervention is needed that way is critical.
Well, I come to you, but then
we use the most unreliable thing for the most critical part, which is
where.
I'm from, the scaling issue.
You have that in trouble as well.
In fact, I'm off to Austin next week.
And actually we were in Austin.
The few of us were in Austin where we jumped in, see, what was that car?
Waymo, a Waymo.
That was my first oh holy shit, that was weird.
That was.
So I don't know if has anyone has anyone used a Waymo before a number of people,
for those who haven't heard of a Waymo's Waymo is like a it's it uses lidar.
It's it's unlike, the the Tessls, which uses, like of cameras.
Yeah. You know, we were in London.
Then out then.
Are they actually here in London. The.
The they after.
Training for like, like along 3 or 4000km
and then they have to,
drive it with all the driver and passenger for like another 500 ish.
And then there we go, super interesting.
Think it's already being trained on the streets.
It should be because the contract they got the contract quite recently I think.
And it's Christmas time so few months.
Back and. They didn't train it.
Super interesting.
Well when we got in one we did scream at first because it's like,
oh my God, I can't control it, I don't like it.
But then the speed at which we got used to it was quite shocking.
And also, how good that car was
driving was until to, until one thing happened
when it tried to park in a place called Terry Black Steakhouse.
Barbecue place.
There was a couple of things where it just got so confused
and tried to do things, and we were like, oh my God, stop this now is ridiculous.
A car was like another car out the way I thought it was parked
and was trying to go round this car, then tried to reverse.
As we were going forward.
It was going back and it's like I need to get out the situation quickly.
There was another one where I think Waymo was,
there was a there's a police car where there's a police standoff,
really some guy lying on the floor, police guns pointing at it.
And then Waymo just looked at it and thought, no traffic. I'm going.
And it drove right, right, either through or past the shooter.
And it's like it's the edge, like 95, 99% of the time it's great.
But as soon as an edge case happens,
that's when that's when you know, shit happens.
But yeah, very interesting point.
Any anyone want to add to the to the good question and answer and.
Review that was.
With, with digital is all first of all I think depends a lot on
like legislation, like who is responsible when things go wrong.
In the end it needs nowadays in most cases, at least in Europe,
it has to be a human.
Somebody is or do we do?
We pointed to the developer that created it like 30,000 miles away, probably.
So somebody needs to make the decision.
If it's the human then it's clear or the company.
But next step your your example of a plane.
You know, that's getting for most airports the landing and takeoff,
which are the most,
well precarious situations where the most dangerous situation
a pilot so in charge and they have their hands on either the steering wheel
or because the mid-air problem is not that's not the problem.
That's totally there's a reason for that.
The pilot is responsible in the engine, and the pilot is straight
and can make split second decision for days.
So it depends on on
what's what's the situation, what is it safe.
And basically it's threat management and risk management in the engine.
And if there's enough proof that a computer can do that
and can do that better than human, then we will probably go there
in a matter of time.
I think there's a trust issue.
I think there's a guardrails issue.
And I think issues that things that will hold the scenario
that you mentioned back will be poor guardrails, poor tests,
which cause problems
that then reduce our trust and that will slow down that that path.
I think what you mentioned, though, is an inevitability.
Once we have the right guardrails and the right tests in place,
I don't see a future I know. I'd love to hear from you.
I'd love to.
I think if we don't,
we are not really, truly unleashing the full potential.
But it's about the fact that,
you know what, 99.99% of the time it'll work.
And when it doesn't work, we deal with it.
But actually, humans will cause great number of problems,
probably in other cases we just need to get to that point
now where we have the guardrails, the proper reviews.
Otherwise
other companies that do that will rip apart companies that don't, unfortunately.
But that's me. I'd love to.
Sorry. I'd love to hear from both of you.
I think there's always going to be a human.
And would you get an open heart surgery with no human ever involved?
But there's a there's a gap between,
a retail place, a retail shop, an open heart surgery city.
On the on the line interpretation of the line critical systems.
Same thing with airplanes.
Same thing with, like, surgeries.
I think there's always going to be one that you mentioned
is going to be someone responsible when things go wrong.
Yeah.
But if we understand where our systems are working,
how the things that will be, then we can give more, autonomy.
So for me, at the end, you should understand
more where things are coming from, what to do if something goes wrong,
if you have that power of your team has that all up, why not go forward?
But if you know
things are going out of control and you don't really know how to go back,
the thing which was said before, right, that if you can go back, if you can reward
the changes made by, automation, why not?
You can try it.
But once you don't know how to control it, how to go back,
and even after one month, you don't know your own architecture
because the encrypted code, which is far from your understanding,
then it's a problem because you cannot go back to what was done.
I'd love to hear this gentleman has a has an incorrect opinion.
I'd love to hear that. When he was shaking his head when I was told.
To ask the original question, I will just confuses more than humans.
When you have disproved Turing in all computable numbers.
What he did was he created a paradox and proved
you cannot resolve that sort of paradox
and unacceptable 99.2%.
That's before I'm just a computer head of a human.
It has to be able to resolve paradoxes and Turing proof that it counts.
But, But are you talking about blind trust
or are you talking about trusting something enough that it becomes
good enough or better than a human a percentage of the time?
A perception of the time?
Yes. But, I wouldn't expect to absolutely find a very long way.
Other questions.
Yeah, absolutely.
Please speak up if you have a question as well, so that somebody can see
and please put your hand up highest if you've been waiting longest.
I'm going to be a free to use the restroom.
Oh yeah. Absolutely.
So that's one. Two.
I've got a related question to the discussion is really great.
You know, human reliability and navigating the space
between like PR stunts or action called leaks.
And so jumping.
But the discussion right now,
I think is really getting into the heart of the matter.
And I would like everyone understands briefly answer this question.
How would you or how far would you allow,
to go in your organization?
So I certainly see life.
Just briefly.
If everyone of you could not see the amazing.
Healing stuff, I'm happy to start or.
Yeah.
I today
I'm happy for it to make updates to non
critical systems fully autonomously.
Critical systems I would expect
actually even critical systems,
so long as there are enough checks and tests in place
and it's actually not my trust in AI, it's my trust in my tests.
That is that is key.
If I don't trust my test suite, do I trust the junior developer?
Or a senior developer?
On a Friday afternoon after he's had a beer or tea?
It's trust in my.
They say you need breaks in a car to go fast.
And it's about trusting the systems that will stop you from failing.
So non-critical changes
to critical systems or,
any change to a non critical system, I would be happy for,
you know, those to make changes from a personal foot
from a life point of view actually similar similar where
where critical turns into my personal data PII those types of things.
I personally expect that
to really push for like to, to massively increase.
So that actually I would and I am comfortable
for more critical changes to occur only when
the value I get from
it is greater than what would happen if I didn't allow that to happen.
And for me, the 3:00 3 a.m.
other hours are available, but we seem to expect something to happen
at exactly 3 a.m. these days.
The 3 a.m.
issue if it takes me 2 to 3 hours but takes it, I five minutes to to debug,
resolve and fix, I would rather it did that and wake me up.
If it couldn't do something, or if it was trying
to make a change that my guardrails or my tests would say.
This is something which is highly dangerous,
you know, to, to, to, to to check.
But they need to be, again, non-deterministic, sorry, deterministic
tests to validate that those changes.
I I'm comfortable with that.
If you have yeah I.
I, I you I agree with you on my most stuff
but I'm a person that is quite paranoia
and I work at a security company for a reason.
I and mill and like, I'm in the military for a reason.
I don't trust things like.
So I just to assert that I would trust
things to make sure they get dropped beyond me.
But I want to know what's going on, because in the end, I am responsible.
So at this point in time, I want you to hack in.
I want to be the person that clicks on proof that I consciously did it.
That will be a time, but probably it will takes take.
It takes a while for me to do it and to convince me enough
that some of these things will be,
blindly trusted
to not critical systems and and no design critical need or not.
But for now, I'm even the first like ci CD.
Yeah, that's fun, but I want to know if it really works.
You know, I was that person.
Now I trust it, but it takes for me it takes a while because I'm kind of the
kind of guy.
Yeah.
For me, I'm in between for critical systems.
I want to experiment how things,
maybe create God feels, make choices.
What can do automatically?
What can stop based upon the results like that? That's you.
Those are the feedback results.
And so on.
For the critical systems game, I don't want to be bad of nine
and try to see or try to have somebody moving away.
But yeah, I.
Would love to play with not to think of system non-critical thoughts.
Yeah. Like that.
And then tried and tested the kind of scenarios.
Right. This is a lot of patience.
Do allow something.
On the other hand, if we stop something based on what they're going to just
and try to find that right.
Then when I think the system is bit short enough, maybe I can,
take a leap forward and, depending more optimistic.
What did I miss?
I think we have, rather than do it another.
We have one,
we have one more question that I.
Oh, two more questions we can jump into before we have to before we have to jump.
We have and then we have a.
They have opinion and they are able to answer.
Okay.
And actually wanted to open up the perspective a little bit.
We've been talking about how much worse we put in the AI and how much of the you
that we need to give you the loot to trust is doing the work, the job?
Probably that we've been thinking, is that the assumption that the humans
are to keep up with them doing, like the engineering teams.
Right.
And we ought to be, preparing to do a period of time where,
anybody can be an application to the problem,
including people who have absolutely no idea what they're doing.
I'm thinking
might be people say to people that even though they might not be,
you know, building critical systems, you can trust them to try and tap
into your customer base, prospect, other base, things like that.
You know, so my question to you was more like, leveraging.
Yeah. Of course. Right.
And by pulling that way through,
the things I want to get, how do you see your relationships,
as you know, between the engineering teams and those people,
do you see yourself as the kind of the guardians of,
you know, the people who are willing to clean up the mess up to them?
And, how do you how do you see the
well, the balance of trust evolving between engineering or skill teams and,
you know, pool of people who are trying to, you know, be stuck with the I.
You know, take them.
Yeah.
It depends on the team, depends on the company.
They are going to be a lot more,
I think when something becomes easier to do and more people are going to do it.
But there are ways by
which you can have your own website to do for example, your own.
Let's say you have a small business.
You on our website, I want use the I love live I would recommend lovable.
I would not recommend you to deploy it on Kubernetes.
You know.
So if you're using all the infrastructure
to set up for you, getting set up for you,
security or whatever, it's on
being handled on there, and then you can just focus on by going,
you know, making a website, a pretty big organization.
And then obviously guardians in the security is,
you know, you know, security checks in place.
There are people who are going to be, responsible for using the code.
But if it's let's say you're walking.
So I got started.
We have some marketing folks
who we use lavender, for example, for their, presentations.
And that's like, so it depends.
I'm not going to ask them to like, push for the production cost.
Yeah.
It's you know, so it depends like I just I understand
when you say people who do marketing and code.
So it's depends on the context.
Why are you asking the marketing people
to push production in your critical applications.
But if it's just someone who is just like a smaller company,
you know, a single person team or like five people team, you know.
I. I, I think the question is more like,
okay, let's say for people to have access to the client database.
So they need a website that is available for all mockingbird.
And fortunately, it's also available to the rest of.
The world today.
Yeah.
But if you're using client data then your you can't just you
can't just take 1995 or something.
You have to take permissions and necessary.
There's that. You need to have a plan to contain the data.
So I think it's a, I think it's a process that is.
Still maybe on the marketing team, you want to use something
for your presentation.
I know, but I don't need to jump up.
Me personally, I'll just pick up on one very,
very minor point, as if this is a code review.
And I'm picking up at know some color choice of, of a button.
I dispute the fact that everyone can become a developer now.
I love the idea that we are being more diverse
in who can write code, but I think that's the piece that we're opening up.
Anyone can write code now that there's a big difference
between simply writing code and being, a.
Second
and yeah, like it.
Yeah.
But I mean, more like being a complete developer, being someone
who understands the workflow, someone who and I think,
you know, if you look at the if you look at the skills
of what makes a good developer today, is it that they code best
or is it a problem so that they can do things
properly and robustly and test fully and communicate
well and, and, you know, understand the solution
fits the problem and work with feedback the user or customer.
So, so I think all that oh,
I love the fact that there is vibe code, throwaway stuff.
I completely agree,
though, that there are limits in terms of which that becomes dangerous.
And it's again, it's the breaks to go fast.
We can empower these teams like our legal team Stephanie created.
It created a, a skill.
And she's she's doing a whole bunch of legal work with contracts and stuff
like that with a skill that essentially, you know, does number incorrectly.
And all these types of wonderful things.
But it's about guidance. It's about allowing
the it's about allowing AI to do things within boundaries.
And that's that's the it's it's empowering given certain things are in place.
Yeah. Yeah. One question.
I think a whole cat is saying, how does this make a.
Good next. Yeah, I think a lot of
my as I said, I think, what
about the same kind of to the experience so many six months ago, a year ago,
the feedback on people's ideas of six months ago changes.
Okay.
Like if I put it together here that we were good to all,
even this three months ago.
Recently models now living inside of a repository
kind of coding like pretty hair that I very much obviously envisage
a future
where we all very much as humans in a way, even from a performance perspective.
Closing thoughts just came up yesterday smushing all the vegetables,
on Wednesday, I believe it's gonna be better
if I have development anywhere in this room.
So if you take that socialization that they did give the example
I left for labs and I looked at insurance companies underwriting arrangements.
So if we have this, this paradigm
where agents are right, you want to kind of code itself.
But what kind of infrastructure changes too much a Pizza
Hopkins not to allow nothing to exist to that.
Do you think that would be like
it really emerges that otherwise not necessarily from a security perspective,
but what if it is a default better than humans?
So like, oh, we got software to have
somebody have a software engineer like what?
What needs to happen to allow.
The health and safety.
Well, we're all looking at each other.
Some.
For for what what what is safe
safety is, is, is again a broad perspective safely is it
the more we the AI,
the more tokens we burn, the more power we burn.
Is that safe?
Depending on if you look at safety and regulations or the environment.
So what is safety that we can we can we can argue about about about that
all day.
But what I think is happening is, first of all, who is responsible.
And I said up before, that is the most important because things will go wrong
even with the best developer, even with the best things will go wrong,
because she didn't foresee that coming.
And what did you put in place to intervene?
Did you put things like,
how do you send observability in place that you can
you can intervene and when do you intervene?
Does the does the model know the model?
Maybe not know today, but a newer model does.
We don't know.
And I think the part of the problem is the scalability for the human interaction.
For now, because we can produce code as we as we can but can't do
what can we context rich enough that all of my ten agents, I can review them?
I don't think so.
So we need to learn to live with that reality.
And what are we doing?
Is more code actually more productivity.
And then I come back to this is what is productivity.
And this is we're talking so much in general terms that this is the
this this depends on on what you're looking for.
So there is no clear answer for that.
And only yet the future will be like.
Yeah, I don't,
I don't think there's much of for I mean in the end it's just
people used to like assembly of us
that can see, for example,
and assembly again, more than 20 languages.
You have to be garbage collection and and get Kubernetes.
You don't have to orchestrate things.
You have to manage your containers on. Wait, wait, what do you think?
What do you think of your ID O'Reilly or something?
I think it's.
Going she's about this I yeah, I think so
even let's say you reach a perfect state and just do anything.
You're it's like perfect.
There's just going to be like decisions that humans have to make,
God kind of thing for you in terms of intuition, in terms of vision.
You want to have it, you want I need a human.
But I'm not sure I agree.
I, I think I think.
Well, the the world will keep changing.
I mean, look at the last four weeks.
What happened in the world, what we did
thought it would happen like five years ago.
So the world will change.
The the models are trained on stuff that are made is at least four weeks
or months old.
So we need to intervene in certain ways that will be the bottleneck.
Again, I will never get emotions. I,
I. Think I mean fundamentally like the
if you read the business and before say they're going to define the problem.
It it's like people often try to like apply this to this human
narrative to the computer.
This is not the idea in general.
In reality, if you give it a
like lot signal, a lot of context, and I'm gonna come off a few moments
later, I don't see a world in which that doesn't meet all I call human.
Approach to text.
But then you set a lot of context.
Context is already contradicting each other.
In most cases.
The more context you give it, the more it depends on how you look at the world.
So everything is bound by culture, by how you are
raised, by what are the other laws and radio regulations.
And that can be different in the UK here versus a, well,
let's say Southeast Asia, because we have we have different ways of working.
So that is always a thing we need to take into account in the world keeps changing.
So I think humans will always be involved, maybe not by taking the code,
but at least somewhere in this process.
Where you still have to get a little too.
So in New York.
I think, I think my perspective probably sits in between
the panels of yours here, where I think, like I do agree,
the levels of abstraction that we have kind of like,
you know, seen over the years where going from, you know, machine code
to assembly to, to, to an interpreted language
and then continuing continuing higher and higher.
I think what we're seeing now is such
a revolutionary step beyond that, it's not just a new format.
It's it's something that, you know,
I don't want to say it thinks for itself, but it's effectively
doing a good enough job that we we believe it thinks for itself.
I think it will continue.
It will plateau at some point. But I think the difference is
the agents and the LMS
today are taking over a coding task
whereby they can approximate what they think we want them to do,
but our role should switch
from producers of code to creators.
And I don't think AI is taking that from us to certainly not today.
Maybe at some point in the future, maybe, but today we need to embrace the thing
that makes us really valuable, which is we have users.
At the end of the day,
those users have needs and we can we as humans understand those needs.
Most we can problem solve and understand this is what I believe we need
because we understand humans better than I will.
In terms of, you know, interpreting that and suggesting and, you know,
I want to create an app that does this, and this is how I believe that this person
is going to want this, given hundreds of different dimensions, an understanding
in my mind, the different levels and weights that they should carry.
I don't think an AI
soon will be able
to do that kind of stuff longer term.
I mean, geez, I hope to be retired by that point.
And, I can see this. Yeah, yeah.
What you're describing is like, tacit knowledge of, like, how to be sorry.
Yeah.
I think your point is essentially like, how do you encode tacit knowledge?
It's not necessarily a extremely interesting
I totally if any of you guys have
I take on that specific part, not just in general.
How do you get
the things that would be feasible to encode this
type of, tacit knowledge, not just access to the data?
The conversations about decoding the messages you have?
You think it's going to be possible?
I mean, I mean, that's going to be that's going to be so close to an AGI,
which honestly, we are like the in my opinion,
we are so far away from AGI, it's unbelievable.
But in fact talking with Logan.
So Logan Kilpatrick is oh God. What is he.
He work.
He works for Google DeepMind is a product.
He leads a certain area of their product in that he used to work for OpenAI.
Now he works for, Google DeepMind.
One of the things he said was,
AGI isn't going to be like,
a magical unleash AI unveiling of a model.
It's going to be a product offering
of maybe a number of different features from a number of different groups.
Maybe it's this environment that feels like AGI
actually delivers
a lot of what we expect AGI will, but it's going to be an environment not,
not this revolutionary model which all of a sudden bagged its AGI.
And I think we will get close to that.
But there's going to be a plateau.
I'm sure we're going to hit a plateau where it's like,
it's going to be good enough for, development and things like that,
but we are going to need to, to, to, to be that creator in charge of it.
I don't think until we hit an AGI, what you describe,
we're really going to see
and I
to be honest,
we need to
it's a completely different way of doing AI than what we're what we're doing now
with other labs. In my opinion.
I think most. Companies don't know what they're doing.
You see standardized failures.
It's like I'm doing this game all that.
They're hacking it. And then Kubernetes has been out years.
I still don't know what I'm doing with that person.
And you see the same. Thing with with security people.
People are making the same mistake they had 20 years ago.
But now I was
like, let's look, let's spend time.
If you want to fly away, you want to know more about the security.
There's the age theory engineering.
Now, wonderful people are involved in security.
There's also another issue of identity.
Anyhow, age is how you solve that problem.
I don't think anyone to solve it.
Some people who are doing it like
it's like an arc, they're working on ideas, teleport.
And that's good stuff. But yeah.
Also, we need to
wrap, but, not wrap up, but we're going to wrap up.
I'm not doing that. We're going to wrap up.
We're going to stay hopefully for a little while.
Let's continue the conversation. Do you know what this has been?
I hate it when panels maybe we have been talking too much,
but there's been so much interaction I think has been really, really valuable.
I just want to ask, ask very quick question of everyone on the panel.
I would love for a very short answer like we did at the very start.
Most to wrap up a little bit, but let's say
someone in this room is, you know, using a coding agent
to deploy a fix or a new feature or whatever it is to production.
What's that?
What's the one concrete thing that you would advise people
absolutely have to do that isn't necessarily obvious,
that you think people really need to hold in high regard today
as part of that process of releasing something to production,
who looks less prepared?
Let's start with Brian.
Make sure that, your newer developers
also know what you're doing and that you are not blame.
And like that stuff that you do today that you are so proud of, that
your future self will be proud of you. That's one.
And the second thing
is that the new developers that are coming, that thing
and that that can come into your company and fix your stuff,
also see that code and I think that's fair or that's that's good.
And you can explain that to that because you need to continue.
I think the continuation is the most important.
I think, the.
Extension to what Brian said is it's not about
automating everything, but preserving the knowledge.
The more we are automating, we are going far away from knowledge.
Although we are saying that we will update documents automatically.
You will do all everything, the architecture automatically.
But in real terms, we are losing the knowledge
even within the developers who are actually doing that by putting.
So I think it doesn't matter what kind of agent do you create?
You create code, you fix your code, you analyze that knowledge.
Preserving elements is the most important task, you know.
Come to my own. Your point?
What makes you productive?
Is it just churning code?
Figure out one.
Started start and continue.
Yeah.
Great. Great. Great answer, great question.
Question and answer.
For me, I'd say a lot of what we talked about here, like the best way
to preserve knowledge
so that it's in a human readable sense and in a readable sense.
Context skills.
Let's make sure, we put guidance policies, ways of working, skills
because you would onboard a human and you develop to your team,
you need to do exactly the same thing to an agent.
And the way to do that, write it down in skills, evaluate those skills,
version those skills, distribute them, to your team so that you will work as,
as one.
Awesome.
Thank you very, very much. First of all, thank you.
Thank you. And a massive thank you to